체스터스 밀은 평범한 마을이었다
JULIA: Chester's Mill is a place
like any other.
적어도 얼마 전까지는
At least it used to be,
수수께끼의 돔이 덮히기 전까지는
until we were cut off
from the rest of the world
by a mysterious dome.
(cows bellowing)
투명하고, 부술 수도 없으며
Invisible, indestructible,
빠져나갈 수도 없다
inescapable.
완전히 갇혔어
We're trapped.
우리는 이 돔의 정체에 대해
전혀 모르고 있다
JULIA: We don't know where
it came from or why it's here,
돔이 이 마을을 덮고 있는 상황에서
but now that we're all trapped
under the dome together,
더 이상 숨길 수 있는 비밀은 없다
none of our secrets are safe.
(shouts, grunts)
여기서 묵게 해주셔서 고마워요
Thanks again
for letting me crash here.
제 남편은 지금 여기 없지만
분명 돌아올 거에요, 바비
My husband isn't here,
but he'll turn up.
You'll see, Barbie.
지난 줄거리가 3화 때 방영되었던 내용과 똑같네요
(shouts)
(gunshot)
저건 절대 없어지지 않을 거야!
That thing
is never going to go away.
(gunshots, bullets ricocheting)
안 돼!
Oh, no. No.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(footsteps approaching)
좋은 아침
Morning.
괜찮으세요?
Feeling okay?
네, 그냥 두통이 있어서요
Yeah, it's just a headache.
스트레스를 받게 되면
항상 이러더군요
I get them sometimes
when I'm stressed.
약이 다 떨어졌던데요
Yeah, you took the last one.
'디 약국'도 문을 닫았던데요
Dee's Pharmacy is closed.
주유소에 아스피린이
있을지도 몰라요
Maybe the gas station
has aspirin.
우연히 마을을
지나가던 사람치고는
You know this town pretty well
이 마을에 대해
정말 잘 아시는군요
for someone
who's just passing through.
'디 약국'은 기억하기
쉬운 이름이잖아요
Dee's is not really
a hard name to remember.
라디오 방송국에
가 보려고요
Think I'll go over
to the radio station.
그럼 같이 좀 타고 가요
All right, well,
I'll catch a ride with you.
다들 주목, 명령이 들어왔다
마을을 떠나지 말라
(over bullhorn): All right,
everybody, orders are in.
다들 짐을 싼 후
이 곳을 떠난다
Pack it up, we're out of here.
우릴 두고 가지 마
이 놈들아!
MAN:
Hey, you can't leave!
(overlapping shouting)
물러서요, 올리
물러서요
Back away, Ollie, back away.
돔에 가까이 있으면
다칠 수 있어요
This thing can really hurt you.
군이 왜 떠나는 거죠?
OLLIE:
Why is the military leaving?
우리는 미국 시민이라고요
We're American citizens.
저들은 우리를
보호해줘야죠
The military is
supposed to protect us.
다들 주목하세요!
LINDA:
Everybody, listen!
저도 여러분의 심정을 이해하지만,
I understand that you're angry,
지금은 해산하셔야 돼요
but I'm gonna ask you
to disperse.
(overlapping shouting)
당장요!
Now!
사악함과 자만심으로
차 있는 삶을 살며
You weep for mercy
자비를 구걸하고 있군요
when you've lived lives
of wickedness and pride.
신은 당신들의
말을 듣지 않습니다
God does not hear you.
신은 우리의 주인입니다
He is the master,
모두 신의 의지에
굴복하게 될 거요
and you will bend to his will.
-돌아가요, 이건 도움이 안 돼요
-그들은 울부짓지만,
Go home, this is not helping.
"There they cry,
사악한 인간의 자만심때문에
그 누구도 답해주지 않고 있어요
"but none giveth answer
because of the pride
of evil men."
이 돔은,
새로운 에덴 동산을 위한
This dome is his wish
신의 소망입니다
for a new Eden.
무슨 일인가?
What the hell's going on?
군이 떠나고 있어요
Military's leaving.
3일이 되도록
군인들은 아무 말이 없어요
It's been three days
and no answers.
주민들은 공포에 차 있고요
Folks are getting scared.
그런 상황에 총을 빼드는 게
도움이 되겠나?
You think pulling a gun
is gonna reassure 'em?
들어보십시오!
지금 당신들을 탓하는 건 아닙니다
All right, all right, I don't
blame you for wanting answers.
우리 모두 돔의 정체에 대해
궁금해하고 있지만
We all want to know when
this thing is coming down,
이러는 건 도움이 안 돼요
but this is not helping.
정부는 우리를
이 안에서 썩게 내버려두고 있어
OLLIE: Government's
left us here to rot.
우리가 왜 당신을 믿어야 하지?
You're a councilman, Rennie.
당신을 믿을 이유는 없다고
Why should we trust you?
왜냐면 정부는 저 밖에 있지만,
나는 돔 안에 있잖나
Because they're out there,
Ollie, and I'm in here.
이제 제발 보안관의 명령을
따라주십시오
Now please listen
to the sheriff.
정보가 들어오는대로
바로 알려드리겠습니다
Soon as we know what's going on
out there, so will you.
집에 돌아가세요
Go on home.
(sighs)
자네 이성을 잃을 뻔 했어
You almost lost 'em.
저는 잘 통제하고 있어요
I had it under control.
군중들에게 총이라도
쏘려고 했던 건가?
What are you gonna do--
open fire on the crowd?
린다?
Linda?
이런
Whoa, excuse me.
괜찮은건가요?
괜찮으세요?
Is she all right?
You okay?
-일단 여길 벗어나봐요
-차로 데려갑시다
Let's get out of here.
Let's get her to a car.
(grunting)
(door opens)
(door closes)
편한 옷을 좀 가져왔어
Brought you some
comfortable clothes.
그리고 깜짝 선물이야
And a surprise.
(sniffs)
Hmm.
우리가 처음 무도회 갔을 때
네가 입었던 옷이야
You wore this the
first time we danced.
주니어 무도회에서
Junior prom.
너 정말 예뻤었는데
You were so beautiful.
내가 예뻐보이면
너도 기분 좋지?
You want me to look beautiful?
나는 좋은데
I don't mind.
너 다시 예전의 앤지처럼
행동하기 시작한 거 같아
You're starting to act
like the old Angie I knew
before the dome came down.
뒤 돌아봐
Turn around.
어서 돌아봐
너 상태가 많이 좋아진 거 같아
I think you're getting better.
약간의 신뢰와 인내심만 있으면
완전히 회복될 것 같아
With trust and a little
patience, I'll get her back.
그렇지, 앤지?
Right, Ange?
앤지?
Ange?
(screams)
(both grunting)
주니어, 미안해
Junior, I'm sorry.
-거짓말 마
-아냐, 정말 미안해
No, you're not.
No, I'm sorry.
진작에 알았어야 했어
I should have known.
넌 좋아진 게 아니야
You're not better.
좋아진 척 했던 거지
(gasps)
You're just pretending.
주니어, 제발 나 좀
내보내 줘
Junior, please let me out.
아무에게도 말 안 할게
I won't tell anyone.
이 일은 다 잊어버릴게
I will forget everything.
제발, 정말로 다 잊어버릴게
Please, I will forget
about everything.
제발...
Just...
제발 나가게 해 줘
just let me out.
네가 준비만 된다면
언제든지 나갈 수 있어
You can leave
whenever you're ready.
(door opens)
하지만 그 전에는 안 돼
But not before.
도와드릴까요?
Can I help you?
전 신문 편집장
줄리아 셤웨이인데요...
Uh, I'm Julia Shumway, I'm
the editor of the weekly...
목소리 들으니 알겠네요
Oh, yeah, I recognize
your voice.
라디오로 소식 전해주시던 분이죠?
You're the lady that's been
doing the news on the radio.
그거 때문에
필을 찾고 계신 거에요?
That why you're
looking for Phil?
-필이요?
-필 부시요
Phil?
Phil Bushey,
당신이 방송했던
방송국 DJ말이에요
the DJ you work with
at the station.
이 차는 필 꺼에요
지금 집에 있을 거에요
That's his car;
he's got to be home.
이건 제 남편 차인데요
That's my husband's car.
필!
Phil!
(sighs)
무슨 일이죠?
What is all the racket?
왜 당신이
피터의 차를 갖고 있는 거죠?
What are you doing
with Peter's car?
저한테 팔았으니까요
He sold it to me.
Oh.
왜 이러지?
I feel like crap.
필!
Phil.
여기 좀 도와줘요!
I need some help!
발작을 한 번만 했다면
별 일이 아니지만
One seizure happens,
maybe it's no big deal.
3일동안 2번이나 했기 때문에
정밀 검사를 받아 봐야 해
Two seizures in three days
buys you both a full workup.
엄마, 난 괜찮아
Mom, I feel fine.
네, 저도요
Yeah, me, too.
그래, 그렇지만 혹시 모르잖니
I know, but we have to be sure.
죄송하지만,
저도 의사인데
Excuse me, I'm a physician.
쟤네 발작의 원인이
전염성 질병이란 생각이 들거든요
We may be dealing
with something infectious
that's causing seizures
in both of them.
혈구 수치 검사랑
뇌전도 검사를 좀 해 주세요
I want you to do a
blood count, an EEG,
음성반응이 나오면
MRI도 찍어주시고요
and if they're negative,
get them MRIs.
혈구 검사랑
뇌전도 검사는 되지만,
We can do the blood
and EEG here,
MRI는 웨스트레이크 병원에만 있어요
but the closest MRI is at
the big hospital in Westlake,
그건 돔 밖 10km 거리에요
and that's five miles
outside of the dome.
지금 돔 안에 신경학자는 없나요?
I don't suppose
you have a neurologist.
지금 의사도 거의 없어요
We're fresh out of doctors.
한 분은 베일로
휴가를 가셨고요
Look, one of them's
on vacation in Vail,
다른 분은 차를 몰다가
돔에 충돌하셨고요
the other one drove his Porsche
right into the dome,
셤웨이 선생님은
행방불명이고요
and Dr. Shumway is M.I.A.
-그럼 제가 검사를 진행할게요
-어떤 의사시죠?
Then I'll do the tests.
What kind of doctor are you?
정신과 의사세요
She's a psychiatrist,
그렇지만 인턴 시절때
다 배우셨습니다
but she did her internship
in medicine.
따라오세요
Come with me.
너네 어머니들 되게
추진력있으시다
Your moms are
pretty hard-core.
그 이상이야
You have no idea.
곧 따라갈게, 알겠지?
All right, I'll be
right there, okay?
저기, 주니어
Hey, Junior,
우리 누나 본 적 없어?
you haven't seen
my sister, have you?
돔 데이 이후로
한 번도 보지를 못했네
I haven't seen her
since the dome came down.
앤지?
Angie?
이틀 전 밤에 봤는데
Saw her a couple nights ago.
어디서?
Where?
기억이 정확히는 안나는데
I don't know, around.
볼 일 더 있어?
Anything else, Little Man?
아니
I guess not.
(Barbie and Big Jim grunt)
-무슨 일이죠?
-모르겠어요
What's going on with her?
Not sure.
-갑자기 쓰러지더니 지금은 열이 있네요
-아빠
She collapsed and now she's burning up.
JUNIOR: Dad.
주니어, 손은 왜 그러니?
Junior, what happened
to your hand?
장작을 좀 패다가요
Oh, uh, chopping wood.
도끼가 미끄러졌어요
Ax slipped.
아픈 데는 없니?
Feeling okay?
린다는 왜 저래요?
What happened with Linda?
모르겠다
I don't know.
누가 좀 도와 줘요
NURSE:
We need some help.
열과 두통 증상을 나타내는 환자들이
늘고 있어요
More people are coming in
with fever and headache.
무슨 일이 있는 거죠?
BIG JIM: What are
we dealing with here?
모르겠어요
독감인 거 같기도 하고
I don't know, it
could be the flu.
지하에서 침대를
더 가져와야겠어요
We need to get more cots
up from the basement.
제가 가져올게요
I'll get it.
주니어, 바비를 좀 돕거라
Junior, help Barbie.
기절했어요
He passed out.
3번 구역으로
NURSE:
Put him in Bay 3.
린다는 왜 저래요?
What happened to Linda?
린다도 기절했어요
BIG JIM:
She passed out, too--
필이 기절한 것과
연관이 있는 것 같군요
probably from the same thing
that happened to Phil.
이게 무슨 일이죠?
What's going on?
저도 알면 좋겠군요,
셤웨이 부인
I wish I could tell
you, Mrs. Shumway.
마을에 의사가 없어요
The town's out of doctors.
당신 남편이 있었다면
좋았을텐데
Sure could use your husband.
(panting)
도와줘요!
Help!
Help! Help!
(screams)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Under The Dome
Season 1 Episode 4
Outbreak
질병
Ow!
딸아, 조용히 좀 있거라
Sweetheart, keep still.
엄마도 한 번 맞아봐
Oh, you suck at this.
가만히 못 있을 걸?
No wonder you became a shrink.
자, 됐다
There, done.
이거 실험실에 좀
갖다 놔 줄래?
Will you run this to the lab?
응
Sure.
이건 어떻게 작동하는 거에요?
So, how's this thing work?
네 뇌에 흐르는
전기 신호를 측정하는 거야
It measures the
electronic activity
in your brain.
정상으로 나오나요?
Is everything normal?
아니, 돌연변이라고 나오는데?
'울버린'같은
Nope, you're a mutant
like Wolverine.
너 엑스맨 영화 알아?
You know X-Men?
나 그런 건 다 알아
I know a lot of stuff.
(both laugh)
노리, 장난치지 마라
Norrie, not now.
넌 정상이야
Your brain's as normal
검사 결과에 특별한 건 없어
as any EEG I've ever seen.
그런데 왜 발작 증세가 있었던 거죠?
Then why'd we have the seizures?
(door opens)
앨리스, 아담스 간호사에게
듣고 와 봤습니다
Alice, Nurse Adams
said you'd be here.
당신 도움이 필요해요
We need your help, right away.
그대로 있어
Stay.
미친 소리같기는 하지만
I know this, uh,
may sound crazy,
당신이 이 마을에 갇히게 된 건
우리로선 다행인 일이었던 것 같군요
but, uh, we're lucky
you got trapped
here in Chester's Mill.
WOMAN:
Excuse me.
(coughing, indistinct chatter)
무슨 일이죠?
What's going on?
당신이 좀 말해봐요
You tell me.
당신 도움이 필요해요
We need your help.
환자를 검사하려면
마스크랑 장갑이 필요해요
Uh, well, I'll need a mask and
gloves before I examine anyone.
둘다 바닥났어요
We're out of both.
항생제는 있나요?
What about antibiotics?
네, 당장은요
We have that for now.
앨리스가 체온을 재 드릴 거에요
WOMAN: Alice is gonna take
your temperature.
알겠어요
MAN:
Okay.
여기서 뭐 하세요?
What are you doing here?
린다가 아픈 거 같아서
짐이랑 같이 데려왔어요
Linda got sick,
so Jim and I brought her in.
그쪽은 여기 왜 오셨죠?
Why? What are you doing here?
저도 당신 친구를 데려왔어요
필 부시요
I just brought in
a friend of yours-- Phil Bushey.
먼저 가 있어봐
곧 따라갈게
Go on up ahead; I'll, uh...
I'll catch up with you.
당신 체스터스 밀에 온게
이번이 처음이라면,
If you've never been to
Chester's Mill before,
필은 어떻게 아는 거죠?
how do you know Phil?
(chuckles)
무슨 말인지 잘 모르겠네요
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
제 물건을 뒤진 건가요?
So you went through my stuff?
당신은 제게 주니어랑
싸운 것에 대해 거짓말했어요
You lied to me about having
a fight with Junior Rennie,
그래서 확인을 해 본거죠
so, yeah, I thought
I would check up
또 다른 거짓말이 있나 없나 말이죠
on maybe what else
you lied about.
제게 설명을 해 줘야 돼요
(panting):
You owe me an explanation.
바비, 그냥 사실대로 말해 봐요
Barbie, just tell me the truth.
Whoa, whoa.
전 괜찮아요, 그냥 두통이에요
I'm okay, I just
have a headache.
이 분을 치료 구역으로
데려 가요
Let's get her
to the treatment area.
침대 좀 저쪽으로 치워봐요
공간이 없어요
Set those cots up down there;
we are getting slammed.
무어 부인?
Mrs. Moore?
린다에요
Linda Esquivel.
3학년 때 제 담임이셨잖아요
You were my third grade teacher.
물론
Of course.
널 기억하지, 린다
I remember you, Linda.
정말 좋은 선생님이셨어요
You were an amazing teacher.
넌 정말 끔찍한 학생이었지
Oh. You were a terrible student.
(chuckles)
돔 때문인 거 같니?
Do you think it's the dome?
지금 우리가 아픈 이유 말이다
Is that what's making us sick?
저도 모르겠네요, 무어 부인
I don't know, Mrs. Moore.
모르겠어요
I don't know.
아빠, 이게 대체
무슨 일이죠?
Dad, what the hell is
going on around here?
나쁜 일이 발생한 것 같아
(sighs)
Uh, some kind of outbreak.
의사 선생님...
Doctor...
이게 정확히 무슨 일인가요?
what exactly is going on here?
제가 보기에는
뇌막염인것 같아요
I think it could be
meningitis.
제 사촌중에 환자가 있었는데,
매우 나쁜 병이에요
My cousin had
that. It's bad.
처음엔 괜찮더니
몇 분 후 위독해지더군요
One minute he was fine,
the next he was dying.
물론 확신은 못 해요
We can't be sure,
요추 천자 키트가 없어서
정밀 검사를 못 했거든요
because the clinic doesn't have
any spinal tap kits,
그렇지만 열이나 목 통증 같은
증상들을 보면...
but the symptoms--
high fever, neck pain,
수막염일 확률이
매우 높아요
photophobia-- I'd be surprised
if it was anything else.
마을에 전염병에 도는 것 같아요
I think we may have
an epidemic on our hands.
전염병이요?
An epidemic?
확산 속도가 얼마나 되죠?
How contagious is it?
매우 빨라요
Very.
환자가 기침만 해도...
If anyone who's sick coughs,
옆으로 옮겨져요
(snaps fingers)
it spreads.
더군다나 망할 돔이
인큐베이터 역할을 하고 있어
This damn dome.
It's like an incubator.
주니어는 대학교에 가면서
Your son probably
got vaccinated
백신을 맞았었나 보네요
저희 가족도 맞았어요
when he went to college;
so did my family.
그럼 우린 안전해요
So, we're okay.
저도 군에 있을 때
맞은 적이 있어요
Yeah, I got mine
in the military.
백신을 맞지 않은 분들은 어쩌죠?
Yeah. Well, what about
those who didn't?
증상이 생기기 전에
Well, if there's no symptoms,
항생제를 먹으면 괜찮아요
swallow an antibiotic
and you're protected.
그렇지만 이미 증상이 나타난 분들은
But for these people
who are sick,
항생제가 더더욱 절실하게 필요하죠
they need antibiotics,
and they need them fast.
보통 몇 시간 안에
항생제를 먹어야 살 수 있죠?
Okay, so then how much time
are we talking about?
11~12시간 정도요
11, maybe 12 hours.
그런데 문제가 있어요
But that's not our only problem.
이 사람들에게 모두 줄만큼
많은 양의 항생제가 없어요
I checked-- we don't have
enough antibiotics
to treat all these people.
'디 약국'에 가 봐요
Dee's Pharmacy.
이봐요
Listen, Doctor.
필요한 물건 목록을
적어 줘 보세요
Give me a list
of what you need.
지금 분명히 말할게요
Let me be absolutely clear:
만약 전염병 환자들이
마을을 돌아다니게 되면...
if these people leave
and it spreads...
그런 일은 절대 없도록 할 겁니다
Well, we're gonna
make sure it doesn't.
의사한테서 목록을
받아 왔어요
Got that list from the doctor.
고맙다
Thanks.
들어가서
Go inside.
문을 지키거라
Guard the door.
아무도 나가지 못하게 해야 돼
Make sure no one gets out.
격리하라는 건가요?
Like a quarantine?
격리던 뭐던 상관없어
You can call it
what you'd like.
아무도 못 떠나게만 하거라
Nobody leaves.
너를 믿는다, 주니어
Counting on you, Junior.
병원 문을 닫습니다
The clinic is now closed.
지금부터 아무도 여길
나가실 수 없어요
No one leaves, you understand?
(crowd murmuring)
아무도요
No one.
(gasps)
(sputters)
(panting)
(whimpering)
(screaming)
(P.A. beeping)
필?
Phil?
응?
What?
어쩌다 당신이 피터의 차를
갖게 되었는지 말해봐요
Phil, I need to know how
you ended up with Peter's car.
피터, 미안해
오늘 밤엔 오두막에 갈 수 없어
Peter, I'm sorry, man, I can't
make it to the cabin tonight.
오두막이요?
Cabin?
무슨 오두막이요?
What cabin?
여기 나와서 뭐 하시는 거에요?
What are you doing out of bed?
이 사람이 피터의 행방을
아는 것 같아요
I think that he knows
where Peter is.
제 남편 말하는 거에요
Uh, where my husband is.
이 분과 말을 해 봐야겠어요
I just need to talk to him.
항생제 효력이 나타날 때까지
Well, okay, give him a few hours
몇 시간만 기다렸다 말하세요
for his antibiotics to kick in.
그리고 부인도 침대로 돌아가요
And you should go back to bed
빅 짐이 약을 가져오기 전까지요
until Big Jim comes back
with your dose.
-도디, 가지마
-이건 환각이에요
Dodee, don't go.
He's hallucinating.
뇌막염 증상 중 하나에요
It's one of the later
symptoms of meningitis.
늦지 않게 병원에 데려와 줘서
정말 다행이에요
It's a good thing
that you brought him in
when you did.
침대로 돌아가요
Go back to bed.
뭐야?
BIG JIM:
What the hell?
젠장맞을!
Damn it!
누군가가 다 가져갔어요
Whoever did this
took everything.
환자가 얼마나 있지?
How many are we up to?
최소 30명은 증상이 악화됬고
At least 30
with advanced symptoms.
20여명이 초기 증상을
보이고 있어
Another two dozen
with early signs.
빅 짐 소식은 아직 없어?
Any news from Big Jim?
아직
Not yet.
자기, 상태가 안 좋아보여
Honey, you don't look well.
넌 정말 괜찮은 거...
Are you sure
you haven't caught...
우린 백신을 맞았었잖아
We got vaccinated, remember?
아프리카로 사파리 여행 갔을 때
When we took
that safari to Africa.
그 때 인슐린 안 먹고 가져왔어
I took my insulin
without eating.
얼만큼 남아 있는데?
How much do you have left?
이 얘기는 나중에 하면 안 될까?
Can we please talk
about this later?
얼만큼 남았냐구?
How much?
며칠 분은 남아있어
Definitely a few days' worth.
알겠어, 내가 먹을 걸 좀 가져올테니
Okay. I'm gonna get you
something to eat,
좀 먹으면서 해
and you're gonna eat it.
(sighs)
캘버트 선생님!
WOMAN:
Dr. Calvert!
(monitor beeping rapidly,
Linda shivering)
린다 체온은 40도로 측정되었고
무어 부인 BP가 떨어지고 있어요
Linda's temp's 104 and
Mrs. Moore's BP's falling.
-항생제는 얼마나 남아 있죠?
-1회 투약량이요
How much antibiotic do we have left?
One dose.
(beeping continues)
린다에게 투여해 줘요
MOORE:
Give Linda the medicine.
전 다음 차례를 기다릴게요
I'll wait till the next round.
이 상황에서 제게 투여하는 건
옳지 못한 거에요
There's no way
I'm gonna take it.
린다에게 투여해 주세요
Go ahead, give Linda the dose.
(shivering)
(siren wailing)
MAN (over radio):
Uh, medical,
this is Rescue One.
-날 나가게 해 줘
-죄송해요
You need to let me out.
Sorry.
제 아빠 명령이 있어서요
Orders from my dad.
상황이 통제되기 전까진
아무도 나갈 수 없어요
Nobody leaves until we get
this thing under control.
주니어?
Junior?
제임스?
James?
넌 이해 못 해
You don't understand.
내 남편 일에
문제가 생긴 것 같아
I think that my husband
might be in trouble.
어떤 문제요?
How?
(people coughing in distance)
그러니까...
What...
(sighs)
내가 아는 건
All I know is that
필이 피터를 오두막에서
만난다고 말했단 거야
Phil said that he was
meeting Peter in a cabin.
제가 바비를 만난 곳이네요
Like the one I found Barbie at?
그게 무슨 말이니?
What are you talking about?
며칠 전에, 바비가
오두막에 가는 걸 미행했어요
A few days ago, I followed
Barbie to this cabin.
스패로우 길 끝에 있는 데요
Uh, end of Sparrow's Lane.
날 나가게 해줘
You need to let me out.
저도 그러고 싶지만,
안 돼요
I wish I could,
but... I can't.
(sign buzzing)
(monitor beeping)
접근 카드를 대시오
Dr.셤웨이
(scanner beeps)
약을 가져간 범인이
누군진 모르겠지만
BARBIE: Well, at least
whoever took all that medicine
멀리는 가지 못했을 거에요
couldn't have gotten far.
-돔 때문에?
-네
Because of the dome?
Yeah.
그리고 그렇게 많은 양이면
And with a haul that size,
차 없이는 안 되었을거에요
there's no way
they're getting away on foot.
트럭이나 밴을
찾아보면 되요
So we're looking
for a truck or a van.
장례식 차는 어떤가?
Or a hearse.
목사를 의심하는 건가요?
What, your reverend?
그자가 뭐 때문에
약을 훔쳐갔겠어요?
The hell would he
be doing with drugs?
좋은 이유는 아닐 테지
Nothing good.
신의 노여움이
불타오르고 있어
His wrath burns like fire.
자네 뭐하는 건가?
The hell are you doing?
신의 계획을 기리고 있네
Honoring his plan.
주민들이 병에 걸렸단 소식을 듣고
When I heard folks got sick,
디 약국에 쳐들어갔지
I broke into Dee's Pharmacy...
자네 정말 미쳤나?
What are you, insane?!
약이 없으면 사람들이
다 죽을 걸세!
People will die
without that medicine!
그게 그 사람들의 운명이야
Those people
are supposed to die.
신의 뜻이라구
It's God's plan.
날 믿게
Trust me.
돔 아래에서
인간이 사느냐 죽느냐는
He's the only one who decides
who lives and dies
under his dome.
신께서 결정하는 거야
그러면 당신도
이런 짓 말아야지!
And there's nothing
you can do about it.
약을 차에서 내리게
Unload the car.
(monitor beeping steadily)
(groans softly)
(sighs)
무슨 일이죠?
What's happening?
간호사들이 자네에게
항생제를 투여해줬어
They gave you antibiotics.
곧 회복할 거야
You should be on the mend soon.
부인은 어떠세요?
And how are you feeling?
나아진 것 같아
I've been better.
만약 자네가 어제...
If you told me yesterday
주니어 레니가 병원에서...
that the idea of Junior Rennie
총을 들고 나대고 있다는
애기를 해줬다면...
brandishing a shotgun
would be reassuring...
(chuckles)
배꼽을 잡고 웃었을 텐데...
...I'd have laughed
my head off.
사실 그와 비슷한
너에 대한 농담을...
Actually, I might have
said that about you
몇 년 전에 하곤 했지
a few years ago.
옛날에 전 마치 선생님
애완견 같았죠?
Wasn't exactly
the teacher's pet, was I?
그런 건방진 말버릇으로?
With that mouth of yours?
설마 그랬을 리가...
(chuckles)
Lord, no.
지금 네 모습을 보렴
But now look at you.
한 마을의 보안관이야
The town sheriff.
전 다른 분들의 후원을
많이 받았어요
I've had a lot of help, though.
특히 듀크 서장님께요
Especially from Duke Perkins.
안식을 누리고 계실 거야
May he rest in peace.
그래도 스스로를
과소평가하진 마렴
But don't sell yourself short.
(exhales softly)
무어 부인?
Mrs. Moore?
(monitor flatlines)
무어 부인?
Mrs. Moore?
도와줘요!
여기 좀 도와줘요!
Help! We need help in here!
심장발작이에요
She's coding.
흉부 압박을 해야 돼요
Starting chest compressions.
하나, 둘
One, two,
셋, 넷, 다섯, 여섯, 일곱, 여덟
three, four, five,
six, seven, eight,
아홉, 열, 열하나, 열둘...
nine, ten, 11, 12...
방금까지 대화하고 있었는데...
I was just talking to her.
(door creaks)
(indistinct chatter)
저리 비켜, 주니어!
OLLIE:
Out of the way, Junior!
네가 우릴 가둬 놓을
권리는 없어
MAN: You have no right
to keep us here.
그 총 하나로
우릴 막을 수는 없을 걸
OLLIE: You can't stop all of us
with that gun.
물러나요
Step back.
WOMAN: Whoa!
MAN: Hey, hey, hey.
(chair clatters)
가자
Let's go.
(gunshot)
(clamoring)
주니어
Junior.
(panting)
댄스모어 씨...
Mr. Densmore...
우리 엄마가 돌아가셨을 때
기억 해요?
you remember
when my mother died?
그리고 아저씨 부인이요
And your wife,
she made that amazing
맛있는 옥수수 빵을
만들어주시곤 했었죠
corn bread.
아저씨 들판에서 기른
옥수수였잖아요
From your own field, she said.
제게 냄비도 주셨었죠
Even gave me the skillet.
기억하지
I remember.
지금은 제가 여기 있죠
Now I'm in here...
총을 들고서,
아저씨랑 함께요
with you, with this.
아저씨를 쏘기 위해
여깄는게 아니라
Not to point a gun at you.
제가 체스터스 밀에 살고 있고,
But because I live here
저도 여러분들 중
한명이기 때문에 있는거죠
and I'm one of you.
우리는 힘을 합쳐서
이 어려움에 맞서야 하고,
We've got to fight
through this thing together
우린 중요한 이유가 있기에
여기 있다는 걸 믿어야 해요
and trust that we're
all in here for a reason.
전 이 마을을 믿어요
I believe in this town.
전 제 아버지를 믿어요
I believe in my dad.
그리고 전 아저씨를 믿어요
And I believe in you.
(door closes)
(drawer squeaks)
오, 피터
(quietly):
Oh, Peter.
(exhales)
(panting)
(camera clicking)
얻을 수 있는 건
전부 다 가져왔어
This is all I could
scrounge up.
저 밖은 꼭 동물원같아
It's a zoo out there.
고마워
Thanks.
땅콩 버터랑 식빵하고 젤리
다 떨어지면 어떡하지?
So what are we gonna do when we
run out of, like, peanut butter
and jelly and bread?
뭘 먹어야 돼?
What are we gonna eat?
그 전에 나갈 수 있을 거야
We'll get out before then.
그나저나 난 생각하고 있었거든...
All right, so, I was thinking...
우리 발작 말이야...
our seizures.
어젯 밤 발작은
우리 둘이 접촉했을 때 발생했어
The last time one happened
was after we touched.
우연의 일치일 수도 있지
Yeah, could've been
a coincidence.
둘 다 우연의 일치였다고?
Both of us?
정확히 동시에 발작을 했잖아
At the same exact time?
(chuckles)
접촉때문에 발작한 건 아닐까?
What if we triggered it?
그래, 근데 그게 말이 돼?
Okay, how would that happen?
나도 몰라, 그렇지만...
I don't know, but...
실험해보자
we should test it.
어떻게...
Like...
다시 접촉해보자고?
touch again?
응
Yeah.
네가 겁난다고만 안 한다면
Unless, you know, you're scared.
겁 안 나
No, I'm not scared.
녹화해 두자
We should film it.
여기 바닥에 앉아 봐
Here. Get on the floor.
알겠어
All right.
혹시라도 바지에 오줌지릴 거 같으면,
But if you pee your pants,
녹화되고 있다는 걸 기억하라고
just know there will be
video evidence.
그건 너도 마찬가지야
JOE:
Same goes for you.
(sighs)
준비됐어?
You ready?
하자
Let's do it.
그냥 바보가 된 기분인데?
Okay. I feel stupid.
(electrical crackle)
(horn honking)
항생제 가져가세요
Got the antibiotics.
수간호사에게
곧장 갖다 드려
MAN: Bring it straight on
in to the charge nurse.
문제라도 있었니?
Any problems in there?
전혀요
Not at all.
(shouts)
(crying)
도와 줘요!
Help!
주니어!
Junior!
(panting)
줄리아는 어딨죠?
So, where's Julia?
전혀 모르겠는데요
Not a clue, man.
제가 어딨는지도
잘 모르겠네요
I barely know where I am.
줄리아에게 무슨 말을 한 거요?
(quietly):
What did you tell her?
(exhales)
-당신에게 뭘 물어봤지?
-기억이 다 흐릿해요
What did she ask you?
It's all kind of blurry,
줄리아 남편에 관한
거였던 거 같아요
but I think it was something
about her husband.
진정해요, 이건...
Relax, it's not like
피터는 아무 말도 안 할거에요
사라졌잖아요
he's gonna say
anything about you. He's gone.
사라졌다는게 무슨 말이지?
What do you mean, he's gone?
말그대로 사라졌다고요
Gone like gone.
요즘 코빼기도 안 보이잖아요
Like "Adios, Peter Shumway."
(grunts)
(exhales, sighs)
한 달 전쯤, 피터가 제게
청부 살인에 대해 물어봤죠
About a month ago, he came to me
asking if I knew any hit men.
Whoa...
당신에게 청부 살인에 대해 물어봤다고?
He asked you about hit men?
저도 알아요
I know. Right?
그래서 그런 건 영화에나 있는 거라고
얘기해 줬죠
And I told him that crap
was only in the movies.
피터는 재정 상태가 안 좋았어요
He was in a bad way.
도둑질을 하기 위해
제게 차를 팔았죠
He sold me his car for a steal.
그래서 전 피터에게 충고해줬어요
I told him if things
were that bad, he should
그 현금을 가지고
버스 티켓을 사서
take the cash and buy the
first bus ticket out of here
다른 마을로 가
새롭게 시작해 보라고요
and start over.
당신에게 피터가 빚을
얼마나 졌는지는 모르겠지만
Sorry, man. I don't know
how much he owed you.
(chuckles)
돌려받으실 수 없을 거에요
You ain't getting
that cash back.
줄리아에게는 어디까지 얘기해 준 거지?
And how much of this
did you tell her?
말하기 힘들어요, 그 때 전...
It's tough to say. I...
거의 정신이 없는 상태였다구요
I was pretty out of it.
(pats shoulder)
피터?
Peter?
(panting)
여기 있었구나
Hey there, Red.
(panting)
왜 내게 말하지 않았어?
Why didn't you tell me?
곧 설명해 줄게
I'll tell you soon.
노리, 일어나 봐
Norrie. Wake up.
뭔가 느껴져?
You feel anything?
아무 기억도 안 나
I don't remember.
비디오 확인 해 보자
Let's check out the video.
되감아 볼게
I'll rewind it.
(beeping)
여기 있어
Here we go.
그냥 바보가 된 기분인데?
NORRIE:
Okay. I feel stupid.
(electrical crackle)
분홍색 별이 떨어져요
BOTH:
The pink stars are falling.
분홍색 별이 일렬로 떨어져요
The pink stars
are falling in lines.
분홍색 별?
Pink stars?
이게 무슨 소리야
I don't get it.
쉬...
Shh...
너 저랬던 거 기억 나?
Do you remember doing that?
아니
No.
전혀
No way.
저게 무슨 뜻이지?
What does this mean?
모르겠어
I don't know.
이걸 아무에게도
말 안해야 할 것 같아
Maybe we're not supposed
to tell anyone.
Why not?
왜?
노리, 일어나 봐
JOE:
Norrie. Wake up.
돔이 그러길 원하지 않으니까
'Cause the dome
doesn't want us to.
무슨 일이야?
NORRIE:
What happened?
뭔가 느껴져?
JOE:
You feel anything?
줄리아 본 적 있니?
Hey. Have you seen Julia?
JUNIOR:
Why?
왜요?
드디어 당신을 버리고 갔나 보죠?
Did she wise up and ditch you?
항생제를 줘야 해
She needs antibiotics.
최근에 줄리아를 본 게 언제야?
When's the last time
you saw her?
몇 시간 전에요
Couple hours ago.
오두막집에 대해 물어보던데요?
She kept asking about a cabin.
그래서 뭐라고 대답했지?
What'd you tell her?
며칠 전에 제가 당신을
목격한 곳이라고 말해줬죠
I just mentioned the place
I saw you a couple days ago.
네 트럭 차키 좀 줘 봐
Give me the keys to your truck.
-싫어요
-이봐
No.
Hey.
네가 경비를 설 때
줄리아가 밖으로 나갔어
Now, she left on your watch.
곧 아파서 죽을 지도 몰라
She's sick
and she will die out there,
그러니 어서 차키 내 놔
so give me the keys
to your truck.
피터...
Peter...
(panting)
(shivering)
이제 됐다
너 정말 용감하구나
All right. You were a brave
little girl back there.
집에 가서 푹 쉬거라
착한 아이군요
Okay. Get home
and get better.
She's good.
Oh. Well, well, well.
자네 정말 죽다살아났군
Look who came back
from the dead.
우리 모두를 구해주셨다고요
I heard you saved the day.
그게 내가 하는 일이잖나
Well, that's what I do.
의원님 아들도
의원님을 닮았더군요
Well, your son takes
after you, too.
그런가?
Oh, yeah?
폭동으로 이어질 뻔한
사건을 막았죠
He stopped what could
have been a full-blown riot.
사람들이 공포에 질려있을 때
주니어가 진정시켰어요
People were freaking out,
and he talked them down.
너 나를 굉장히 닮았구나
Chip off the old block.
직업으로 경관 한 번
해 보는게 어떠니?
You ever consider
a career in law enforcement?
당신이었나요?
Was that you?
뭐가요?
Was that me what?
절 구해준 게 당신이었냐고요?
Was that you who saved my life?
오두막에서 피터에 대해
알게 됬어요
I learned about Peter
in that cabin.
피터가 우리 잔고를
텅 비워놨더군요
We're broke;
he emptied our accounts.
우리 집은 담보로 잡혀있고요
And the house is
in foreclosure.
당신은 무슨 일을 하는 거죠?
So, what were you all into?
마약?
Drugs?
(chuckles softly)
군에서 나온 후 저는...
When I got out of the military,
I did, um...
특이한 일들을 많이 했죠
I had a bunch of odd jobs.
보조주방장도 해 봤고,
Uh... was a line cook.
건설업도 했죠
Construction.
(sighs)
그러다가...
And then, um...
경마 관련 사업을 하게 됐죠...
then I linked up
with a bookie...
웨스트레이크 밖에서요
out of Westlake.
경마 내기 관련된 거요?
Taking bets?
사람들이 빚을 갚도록 하는 일이요
Making sure the people
paid what they owed.
집행관 비슷한 거군요
You're an enforcer.
필같은 사람은...
Guys like Phil owed...
빚을 다 갚았죠
and they paid up,
대부분은 그래요
and most of the time,
it's like that.
피터는 도박같은 거 안 해요
Peter never gambled.
현금은 준비했는데,
아내가 집에 있습니다
PETER (recorded): I've got
the cash, but my wife's home.
다른 곳에서 만나죠
Meet me at the other spot.
5일 전 피터가 보낸
음성메세지입니다
It's his voice mail
from five days ago.
그래서 피터는 지금 어딨죠?
So, where is he now?
제발요
Please.
저도 알아야 해요
I have to know.
틀림없이 해외로 날랐을 겁니다
He must have taken off.
이런 일이 종종 있어요
You know, that
happens sometimes.
이런 사람들 중 몇몇은
너무 깊게 연루되서...
Some of these guys, they
get in so deep, and...
마을을 몰래 뜨곤 하죠
you know, they skip town.
죄송합니다
I'm sorry.
죄송하다고요?
You're sorry?
전 당신을 묵게 해 줬어요
I let you stay in my house.
당신을 믿었다고요
I trusted you.
그런 사과는
아무런 의미도 없어요
Your sorry means nothing to me.
제가 집에 돌아가게 되면
당신도 나가세요
When I get back home,
you better be gone.
이제 다 끝난 건가?
NORRIE: So, is
the outbreak over?
환자들은 다 치료를 받았어
Well, everyone who's sick
has been treated,
뇌막염에 노출된 사람들도
and anyone exposed
to meningitis...
다 항생제를 투여했으니...
got antibiotics.
이제 끝난 거지
So yes, it's over.
너네 둘은 어때?
발작 증세 또 있었니?
How do you guys feel?
Any more seizures?
아니요, 저흰 괜찮아요
No. We're fine.
너넨 오늘 하루 종일 뭘 한 거니?
What have you two
been doing all day?
그냥 이것저것하면서 지냈죠
Oh, you know, just
making out and stuff.
그래
ALICE:
Right.
항상 그놈의 '이것저것'이 문제지
It's the "stuff" that
usually worries us.
완전히 지쳤다
(sighs)
I am beat.
이제 집에 갈까?
Can we go home, please?
집이라고?
NORRIE:
Home?
식당 위에 딸려있는
방이겠지
It's a room above a diner.
더 좋은 생각이라도 있니, 얘야?
You have
any better ideas, kiddo?
저요
Well, I do.
저희 부모님이 모두
돔 밖에 계시거든요
I mean, both my parents
are outside the dome,
그리고 방도 충분해요
and there's more than
enough room at my house.
그러니까...
저희 집에서 묵으셔도 돼요
It's just me, so...
you guys could stay there.
제발 거절하지 마
Please don't say no.
제발
Please?
고맙다, 조
그거 좋겠네
Thanks, Joe.
That'd be great.
물건 들 좀 챙겨 올게
네 차에서 봐
CAROLYN: I'll grab our stuff
and meet you in the car.
♪
자기, 뭐하는 거야?
Babe, what are you doing?
인슐린 훔치는 거야?
Are you stealing insulin?
인슐린이 한 주 분밖에
안 남았다며
You yourself said you only
had a week's supply left.
앨리스, 오늘 일을 생각해 봐
Alice, look what
happened today.
오늘 항생제도
거의 다 떨어졌다고
We almost ran out of
antibiotics for everyone.
우리가 필요한 게
다 떨어지면 어떡해?
What happens when we run out?
너 왜 그러는 거야?
Okay, what's going on?
너 답지 않잖아
You're not acting like yourself.
난 두려워
I-I'm scared.
돔이 평생 안 없어지면 어떡하지?
What if the dome lasts forever?
그러진 않을 거야
It won't.
우린 여기서 나갈 거야
We will get out of here.
곧
Soon.
약속할게
I promise.
정말 괜찮으신 거 맞죠?
You sure you'll be okay?
그래
Yeah.
태워다줘서 고마워
Thanks for the ride.
네
Yeah.
경관님 잘못이 아니에요
(sighs) It's not
your fault, you know.
뭐가?
What isn't?
무어 부인이요
Mrs. Moore.
나를 살리기 위해 돌아가셨어
She died saving my life.
경관님이 이 마을에
얼마나 중요한 사람인지 아셨던 거에요
She knew how important
you are to this town.
우리 모두에게요
To all of us.
중요한 사람은
나 말고도 많아
I'm not the only one.
오늘 네가 한 행동도
많은 목숨을 살렸어
What you did today
saved a lot of lives.
네가 했던 모든 행동 말이야
The way you did it.
듀크가 말했었어
Duke always said
경관이 가지고 있는
최고의 무기는
the greatest weapon
we have as police
주민들을 위하는 마음이라고
is a good heart.
무어 부인 말이 맞아
Mrs. Moore was right.
무슨 말이요?
About what?
우리는 많은 일들을 겪었어
We have come a long way.
(quiet creaking)
(doorknob rattles)
(quiet creaking continues)
사과하러 온 거라면
If you came here to apologize,
그냥 하지 말게
don't bother.
난 사과할 게 없다네
I have nothing
to apologize for.
자네에게...
이걸 주려고 왔어
I came... to
give you this.
수익 중에 내 몫일세
My share of the profits.
프로판 다 가지고 있게
Keep all the propane.
난 우리 사업에서
손을 씻겠네
I'm gonna wash my hands of
our dirty little business.
(laughs)
그러기엔 늦지 않았나,
레스터
Little late for that, Lester.
회개하기에는 늦지 않았어
Never too late to repent.
자네는 이 마을을
살렸다고 생각하겠지
You think you've
saved this town,
현실은 그 반대야
but you've damned them.
자네는 신의 권위에 도전했어
You defied God's will.
죗값을 치루게 될 걸세
And for that, you'll pay.
자네가 오늘 한 일에 대해
You're lucky I didn't
haul your ass into jail
감옥에 처넣지 않은거나
운 좋은 줄 알라구
for what you did today.
이건 운에 관한 문제가 아닐세
Luck has nothing to do with it.
자네 스스로를 해치지 않는 한
나를 해칠 수는 없을 걸세
You can't hurt me
without hurting yourself.
축복이 있기를
God bless.
(door creaks)
(shivering)
(panting)
(gasps)
(grunts)
살려주세요!
Help!
(sobbing):
Help...!
살려주세요!
Help!
(Angie screaming faintly
in distance)
(clattering in distance)
(distant screaming continues)
(crickets chirping)
(door creaks)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
한글자막 by 뒷북()
DC인사이드
기타미국드라마 갤러리